New Wagashi Revives Town
Spring Comes to Kamogawa
New Anti-NEET Strategy
Labor Ministry
Emergency Funding
（アナウンサー）
厚生労働省は—
The Labor Ministry has
allocated special funding
（海崎(かいざき)）えっ？ いや
ニートや引きこもり層の
対策として—
Nah.
I'm about done for the day, too.
俺も もう あがる…—
特別予算を計上しました
to combat the rise in NEETs and shut-ins.
I guess.
かな
This will help support their
return to normal society, and...
これにより 社会復帰を
支援する活動に…
Yeah.
Drinks? Now?
飲むの？ これから？
Okay.
Sounds good.
いいね
（海崎）久しぶりだな 会うの
It's been a while, huh?
Oh, yeah, sorry.
ああ うん ごめん
Yeah, sure.
うん 大丈夫 駅前のあそこな
By the station, right?
もう 会社出るから
15分で着くわ
I'm leaving work now.
See you in fifteen.
Yeah.
うん うん じゃあ
Okay, see you there.
Kaizaki Arata (27), Unemployed
Kaizaki Arata-san.
（面接官）海崎新太(あらた)さん
（海崎）はい！
Yes!
You quit your first job after three months?
（面接官）これ 新卒で入った会社
３か月で辞めちゃってるけど—
どうしたのかな？
What happened?
それは
方向性の違いといいますか—
Well, it just wasn't the
right direction for me.
自分を生かせる場は
もっと 他にあるのではないかと…
I felt I could live up to
my potential elsewhere.
You knew that in just three months?
（面接官）
たった３か月で分かる？
その決断力と行動力も
私の長所だと思っております
The ability to make such decisions and
take initiative is also my strong point.
Arata?
（男性）新太は？
（海崎）はっ…
Anything going on where you work?
（男性）会社で
何か変わったことねえの？
My sister's getting married.
I'm hanging in there, I guess.
俺は 現状維持って感じかな
Hanging in where?
何の現状維持だか
Mom
Hello?
Well, how'd the interview go?
（母）どげんやっとんの
就職試験の結果は？
No good.
ダメじゃった
Huh? Why?!
（母）はあ？ 何で？
Don't ask me. It just didn't work out.
知らんが
落ちたもんは落ちたんじゃけ
（母）ふーん
I hate to kick you when you're down...
（母）あんたなあ
追い打ちかけて 悪いんやけど
Oh, goody.
これ以上 何？
（母）来月から もう
仕送りできんけ
We ain't sendin' you any money
from next month.
（海崎）えっ!?
何っ？ 何で!?
What? Why?!
Where'd this come from?
そんな いきなり言われても
（母）だって あんた
27にもなった息子に—
Son, you're twenty-seven.
正直 いつまでも きちいわ
High time you stood on your own feet.
以上 じゃ！
That's all. Bye.
（海崎）ああっ
ちょ ちょっと待…
Whoa, wai—
俺の人生 どうして
こうなっちゃったんだろう
How did my life turn out like this?
Good evening.
（夜明(よあけ)）こんばんは はじめまして
Nice to meet you, Kaizaki Arata-san.
海崎新太さん
Two-year gap before college.
Finished grad school with a job lined up.
（夜明）二浪の末に大学入学
（海崎）うっ！
その後 大学院に進み 就職
But you quit that job in only three months.
しかし その会社を
たった３か月で退職
While you work part-time to make ends meet,
バイトで食いつなぐも
現在 無職の27歳と
you're twenty-seven and have no steady job.
（海崎）いや…
（夜明）間違いありませんか？
No—
Am I right?
Um...
あの！
誰？
Who're you?
I beg your pardon.
Where are my manners?
これは すみません
申し遅れました
わたくし
リライフ研究所の—
I'm Yoake Ryo,
from the ReLIFE Laboratory.
夜明 了(りょう)という者です
Something smells fishy.
なんか うさんくさい
失礼だなあ 本名ですよ
How rude. That's my real name.
I'll cut right to the chase.
単刀直入に申し上げます
You've been selected as
a test subject for ReLIFE.
あなたは リライフの
被験者に選ばれました
Huh?
We'd like your help with an experiment.
（夜明）ぜひとも 我々の実験に
協力していただきたいのです
ReLIFE?
リライフ？
The experiment will last for one year.
（夜明）実験期間は １年間
その間 海崎さんの生活費は
すべて こちらで面倒見ます
We'll pay for all living expenses
during that time.
（海崎）えっ？
（夜明）そして—
Huh?
And, depending on how things go,
過ごし方次第では—
we might hook you up with a job afterward.
最終的に 就職先の
ご紹介もいたします
Seriously?!
（海崎）マジで!?
（夜明）はい
Yes.
E-Experiment?
What exactly will I be doing?
じっ 実験って 俺は何をすれば？
Oh, I'm thrilled!
わあっ うれしいです
Do I have your attention now?
ご興味 持っていただけました？
ぷはっ
What's this?
（海崎）何だ？ この違和感
Something's off.
I look a little younge—
なんつうか ちょっと若…
（夜明）リライフ研究所の…
ReLIFE Laboratory...
うちで開発した秘薬です
A drug we developed...
You've been selected...
被験者に選ばれ…
Take this, and you'll look like you're in...
これ飲めば
見た目 高校生まで…
見た目 高校生まで
若返れますから
Like you're in high school again!
For a year starting this spring...
（夜明）この春から １年間—
...we want you to be a student,
高校生になって
高校に行っていただきたいんです
and go back to high school!
〜♪
（海崎）
何 飲んでんだ 俺！
Why'd I take it?!
Who in their right mind would?
飲むか 普通！
It's way too fishy!
怪しすぎんだろ！
No way...
まさか！
Hello?
Oh, good morning!
あっ おはようございまーす
早速 飲んでいただけたんですね
I see you took the pill already.
酔ってた勢いでだ
I was drunk.
飲んだの 全然 覚えてねえんだよ
I don't even remember taking it.
That's a deadbeat for you.
さすが 大人のクズですね
Dead—
Well, enough standing around.
Please, come in.
まあ 立ち話もなんですし
どうぞ 中へ
俺の部屋！
It's my place!
（夜明）と ここまでが—
So, that pretty much covers
the school you'll be attending.
海崎さんに通っていただく
高校の説明です
昨日 お話ししたとおり
生活は すべて保障いたしますから
Like I said yesterday,
we'll pay for all living expenses.
ほんとに… 全部？
Really? All of it?
はい
Of course.
High schooler, huh...
（海崎）高校生って 今さら？
Bit late for that, isn't it?
And going to school every day
for a year sounds like a pain.
１年 毎日 学校とか
結構 面倒くせえけど
You're thinking high school
sounds like a pain, aren't you?
“高校生とか面倒だな”って
思ったでしょ？
Will you become a student for a year and
１年間
高校生になって—
今の人生を変えられる
チャンスだと思うか
see this as a chance to change your life?
Or will you get cold feet, back out,
and keep living as a NEET?
おじけづいて
このまま ずるずる—
ニート生活を
続けていくか
どちらを選ぶかは
海崎さん次第です
The choice is yours, Kaizaki-san.
I'm not a NEET.
（海崎）ニートじゃねえし…
It was rough on you, right?
（夜明）実際 もう
つらかったでしょう
Pretending you had a real job
in front of your friends.
会社員のフリをして
お友達と 話合わせるの
Stab
Stab!
引き受けていただけるなら—
If you're ready to accept,
please sign the contract.
契約書にサインを
お願いしたいのですが
None of this seems real at all.
（海崎）
なんか 現実味のない話だけど—
But I've come too far to turn back!
ここまで来たら
なるようになれだ
I can live off this for a year,
これで １年 食いつなげて
うまくいけば 仕事もゲット！
and if all goes well,
I'll get a job after that!
やってやろうじゃねえか
Fine, you're on!
I'll do this ReLIFE thing!
リライフ！
（夜明）
はい よいリライフにしましょう
Great. Here's to a good ReLIFE.
Thank you.
よろしくお願いします
（女子生徒）あっ おっはよー
Oh, good morning!
I don't belong here...
入りづれえ
（女子生徒）あっ おはよう
（海崎）うっ
Hey! Good morning!
Good morning!
First year would be one thing,
but I'm starting out in third?
（海崎）
１年ならともかく ３年って…
No. Stop freaking out.
いや 何ビビってんだ 俺
They're kids. Ten years younger.
ここにいるのは
10も下のガキだ
Good. Secured a seat in the back.
よし 後ろの席を確保
Um...
（日代(ひしろ)）あの
（海崎）あっ…
（日代）そこ 私の席なんですけど
That's my seat.
（海崎）えっ？
（日代）黒板に名簿が
The names are posted on the blackboard.
出席番号順で
席 決められています
We've been assigned seats
according to our roll numbers.
うっ！
ああ そうだったんですか
O-Oh, is that so?
ありがとうございます すいません
Thank you.
Sorry for troubling you.
（海崎）早速 恥を！
Already embarrassed myself!
しかも 思わず
敬語使っちまった！
And I accidentally used formal speech!
Here.
ここか 窓際の前から４番目
Fourth seat, window row.
Yo, Yoake!
（男子生徒）よっす 夜明
We're in the same class again!
（男子生徒）また同じクラスじゃん
（海崎）ん？
（夜明）おっ よろしくー
Yeah. Let's have another good year.
Yoake?
Nice to see a familiar face!
よ… あけ？
What?!
H-Hey!
なっ… おい！
Okay, take your seats!
（天津(あまつ)）はーい 席について
Amatsu Kokoro
I'm Amatsu, your homeroom teacher.
担任の天津です
専門は 体育
P.E.'s my subject.
I'm a bit nervous because I've never
been in charge of third years before,
受験生を受け持つのは初めてなので
ちょっと緊張もしていますが—
but let's make it a good year.
いい１年にしましょう
（海崎）若い…
俺より下か？ もしかして
So young.
She might even be younger than me.
Well, it's the first day.
じゃあ 最初だし
自己紹介してもらおうかな
Introductions are in order.
（天津）朝地(あさじ)君
（朝地）はい
Asaji-kun.
Yes.
（天津）と 夜明君
（夜明）はい
And Yoake-kun.
Yes.
（天津）じゃんけんで
勝ったほうからで… せーの
Whoever wins rock-paper-scissors starts.
One, two...
（天津･朝地･夜明）
じゃんけんぽん！
Rock, paper, scissors!
（夜明）あっ 勝っちゃった
Oh, I won.
夜明 了です
２年の時も ３組でした
I'm Yoake Ryo.
I was in Class 3 in second year, too.
Huh?
I'm not in any clubs.
（夜明）部活は入ってません
よろしくお願いします
Pleased to meet you.
"In second year, too"?
（海崎）“２年の時も”？
He was a student here last year, too?
去年も ここに通ってたのかよ
What does that mean?
どういうことだ？
えっ もしかして
あの人 大人じゃないのか？
Is he not really a grown-up?
高校生が ほんと!?
いやいや いやいや
Is he actually a high schooler?
No, no, no.
さっきの…
That girl...
日代千鶴(ちづる)です ２年３組でした
I'm Hishiro Chizuru.
I was in Class 2-3.
I'm not in any clubs.
部活は入っていません
よろしくお願いします
Pleased to meet you.
Talk about unfriendly.
（海崎）愛想ねえ…
（女子生徒）日代さんって
あれだよね？ 学年１位の
That's Hishiro-san?
Last year's top student?
Yep, yep.
Oh.
（海崎）へえー
I remember her type.
Good little scholars.
いたなあ
ああいう いかにも秀才タイプ
A year surrounded by these
bright, young things.
こんな若くて まぶしい
高校生の中で １年間
俺 ここにいていいんだろうか
Should I really be here?
This is fraud! Trespassing!
侵入罪とか 詐欺罪とか
Kaizaki-kun.
（天津）海崎君
Kaizaki-kun, you're next!
（天津）次 海崎君！
（海崎）あっ はい！
Right!
I'm Kaizaki Arata.
海崎新太です
I just transferred in this year.
今年から編入してまいりました
なので 部活も入っておりません
So I haven't joined a club.
I'm nervous because I'm in a new
environment, but I hope to have
分からないことが多く
不安ではございますが—
a great year with you all.
よろしくお願いいたします！
A transfer student?
（男子生徒）編入生か
（男子生徒）なんか カタい
Why is he so formal?
（海崎）自己紹介とか チョロいわ
Introductions are a piece of cake.
（狩生(かりう)）狩生玲奈(れな)です
I'm Kariu Rena.
すみません ちょっと風邪気味で
Excuse me. I have a bit of a cold.
I'm on the volleyball team.
Nice to meet you.
バレー部です
よろしくお願いします
Guess I should start with remembering
the names of the people sitting near me.
（海崎）一応 周りのやつから
覚えていくか
Kariu. The cougher.
狩生 せきの人
狩生 せき… と
Kariu. The cougher.
I'm Oga Kazuomi. Part of
the Going Straight Home Club.
（大神(おおが)）大神和臣(かずおみ) 帰宅部でーす
よろしくお願いしまーす
Glad to meet you all.
Oga the showy.
（海崎）大神 チャラい
Showga?
チャラオーガ
I'm Onoya An.
（小野屋(おのや)）小野屋 杏(あん)です
私も 今年からの編入です
I transferred in this year, too.
今朝 早速 ちょっと道に迷って
遅刻しちゃいました
I already got lost on the way here
and was late for school.
But it's great to be here.
どうぞよろしくお願いします
Guess I'm not the only transfer student.
（海崎）
俺以外にもいるんだ 編入生
編入生同士
よろしくね 海崎君
As fellow transfer students,
let's help each other out, Kaizaki-kun.
ああっ はい こちらこそ
Uh, yeah, sounds good.
Transfer buddy, Onoya.
（海崎）編入生仲間 小野屋
Buddy?
仲間 これって…
Wait...
I...
じっ ＪＫと 合法で
お近づきになれちゃうんじゃ
High School
Girls
I can legally be friends
with high school girls?
Legal
なんか興奮する やばい！
Crap, I'm getting excited!
Well, now that we're done
with the introductions...
（天津）じゃあ
自己紹介が終わったところで…
Japanese
Math
English
すぐにテストを始めます
Let's get the tests started!
Tests? I wasn't told about this!
（海崎）
テスト？ 聞いてねえ！
（天津）机の上 全部しまって
Clear your desks.
I don't want to see
anything but stationery.
筆記用具だけにしてね
（海崎）けど まあ 俺
大学院まで行ってたし—
But, hey, I went to grad school.
大人だし—
I'm a grown-up.
Maybe I'll actually do all right.
思ったより
出来ちゃったりするもんかな
I forgot my pencil box!
筆箱 ねえじゃん！
（夜明）あっははははっ
Students always have one in their bag.
（海崎）カバンに筆箱なんていう
学生なら当たり前の習慣を—
いつ なくすんだろうな
大人って
When do adults forget that habit?
What are you doing, Kaizaki-kun?
何してるの 海崎君
早く カバンをしまいなさい
Put that bag away.
あ… えっと
これは その…
Um, I...
Well, uh...
（天津）ん？
海崎君 ちょっと カバン見せて
Kaizaki-kun, let me
take a look at your bag.
（海崎）え？ あっ どうぞ
Huh? Oh, go ahead.
Oh, I get it.
（海崎）ああ これは
不正を仕込んでるって疑われたか
She thinks I'm trying to cheat.
むしろ 何にも持ってねえんだけど
But there's nothing in there.
海崎君…
Kaizaki-kun...
はい？
これは 何？
What is this?
タバコ… ですけど
A pack of cigarettes. What about it?
“ですけど”!?
"What about it"?!
（海崎）
何だよ タバコぐらい… で…
What's with them? It's just cigarettes...
N-N-N-N-No, this is just...
あっ ああっ ちっ 違うんです
これは その！
Right! I just brought it out of habit!
そう！
いつもの癖で！ あっ…
（天津）“いつもの癖”？
（海崎）うっ…
"Out of habit"?
はあ… テストを始めます
Let's start the test.
Kaizaki-kun.
海崎君
You. Staff room. After school.
放課後 職員室ね
Right.
はい
（女子生徒）不良なの？
（女子生徒）意外
A delinquent?
Didn't see that coming!
（男子生徒）編入生 怖いな
He's kinda scary...
Worst first day ever...
（海崎）最悪だ 初日から
つうか こんな
さらし者みたいな
Shamed in front of everyone...
（大神）もしもーし
Hello?
You okay?
大丈夫？
とりあえず これ
後ろに回してくんないかな？
Pass these back.
Right.
ああ… はい
Here.
ちょっ 自分の分 自分の分！
Wait, take one for yourself!
（海崎）ああっ！
（男子生徒）また あいつ？
Him again?
（海崎）すいません… へへ
（女子生徒）何やってんの？
Sorry.
What is wrong with him?
はい 始め！
Okay! Begin!
Okay, I've gotta use these tests
to reclaim my good name...
（海崎）こうなったら
このテストで 何とか汚名返上を…
筆箱ーっ！
No pencil box!
I can't tell the teacher now!
この空気の中 先生に言うか？
What do I do?!
どうする 俺！
狩生… さん
Kariu-san?
ありがとう
Thanks.
Okay, break time.
いったん休憩ね
（生徒たち）はーい
Um, Kariu-san.
（海崎）あの 狩生さん
（狩生）ん？
Thanks.
ありがとう
どうなることかと思った
I was in real trouble there.
No biggie. Feel free to keep 'em
till the tests are over...
別に… よかったら
テスト終わるまで ど…
（せきこみ）
（海崎）あっ 大丈夫？
You okay?
（狩生）大丈…
Fine.
Maybe you should have stayed home.
無理しないで
休んでもよかったんじゃ
And miss the first day? Don't be stupid.
（狩生）初日から休むとか
バカ言わないでよ
Stu—
（海崎）バッ！ くっ…
（狩生）それに—
And...
I can't miss these tests, no matter what.
このテストだけは
絶対に休めない
Kariu really hates losing.
（大神）
負けず嫌いだからね 狩生は
（狩生）はあ？ 何それ！
（海崎）おっ…
Who asked you?
These tests decide who gets to be class rep.
このテストで
１学期の委員長が決まるんだよ
狩生は 去年
３学期とも委員長
Kariu held that position
for all of last year.
She always had the top score in our class.
クラスで ずっと１位だったもんな
えっ すごっ
Wow.
But this year,
（大神）でも 今年は
学年トップの日代さんと—
she's in the same class as Hishiro-san,
the top scorer in our grade.
同じクラスになってしまった
So she's all fired up now
and couldn't call in sick.
そりゃ 休んでもられないし
燃えますよってわけ
Quit running your mouths!
勝手に ベラベラ
しゃべんないでくれる!?
（海崎･大神）すいません
Sorry!
ん？ 何で俺まで？
Why me, too?
（狩生）うるさい！
（海崎）ええ…？
Shut up!
（女子生徒）先生 さようなら
Bye, Sensei!
（天津）はい また明日
See you tomorrow!
Finished...
（海崎）終わった
In every sense of the word...
ありとあらゆる意味で 終わった
答え ちっとも出てこない
I couldn't answer anything...
Did I ever understand that stuff?
I'm not so sure anymore.
あんなの分かってた時代が
あったのか？
I should go home...
帰ろう
Go home, chug some beers,
and sleep.
帰って ビール飲んで
寝てしまおう
逃げるんじゃないでしょうね
You'd better not be running.
Staff Room
（海崎）忘れてた…
I forgot...
Aoba High Apology Letter
For crying out loud!
（天津）まったく
You are way too young to be smoking!
ダメだよ
若いうちからタバコなんて！
百害あって一利なし
These things'll kill you!
将来 大人になった時
絶対 後悔するんだからね
When you grow up,
you'll definitely regret it.
Grown-up
Uh-huh...
Don't give me that!
“はあ”じゃないでしょ
“はあ”じゃ！
Sorry!
（海崎）すいません
（天津）ほんとに分かってるの？
Do you really get it?
常習ってことは つまり
中毒ってことだから
If you make a habit out of smoking,
you'll get addicted!
10代は特に
依存症になりやすいの
It's especially easy to
get hooked at your age!
やめられないんだよ？
You won't be able to quit!
Amatsu-sensei, how old are you?
天津先生って おいくつですか？
ちょっ 何？ 急に
Wh-Where'd that come from?
I'll be twenty-five this year.
今年 25だけど？
Yup, she's younger.
（海崎）やっぱり 年下
いや 若いっすね
Wow, you're young.
So?
何？ 若いと思って
なめてんだったら ぶっ飛ばすわよ
If you're looking down on me 'cause I'm young,
I'll knock your lights out.
I-I didn't mean it like that!
（海崎）そんなんじゃないっすよ
Kids like you must think
twenty-five is super old.
高校生から見たら
25なんて おばさんでしょうに
28 this year
うっ… そんなこと言うやつ
いるんすか？
Did someone tell you that?
失礼だな ははは…
Rude!
But no, I actually think it's impressive.
いや ほんと
すごいなって思うんですよ
You're so young,
but you have a proper job.
そんな若いのに
しっかりした仕事について—
You're a proper teacher.
しっかり 先生やってて
I truly respect that.
ほんと 尊敬します
は… ありがとう
Thanks.
Truth is, often people don't take me
seriously because of my age.
若いってだけで やっぱ
なめられちゃうことも多くてさ
So having you say that is pretty nice.
そう言ってもらえるのは
正直 ちょっと うれしいや
Thanks.
（天津）ありがとう 海崎君
（海崎）はっ
Kaizaki-kun.
Thank you, Kaizaki-kun.
（佐伯(さいき)）ありがとね 海崎君
But...
（天津）でも！
（海崎）あ…
You're still not worming
your way out of this!
それとこれとは 別！
Here, write an apology letter.
I want it tomorrow.
はい 反省文！ 明日 提出ね
あっ はい
O-Okay.
（海崎）はあ 情けな…
Pathetic...
Yeah, pathetic.
（夜明）情けないですね
（海崎）なっ おまっ！
You!
Your first day was a disaster.
初日から 波乱含みでしたねえ
And whose fault was that?!
（海崎）誰のせいだと！
Your own, don't you think?
海崎さんご自身のせいじゃ
ないんですか？
（海崎）うっ！ ぐぬ…
あんた どっちが本当なんだ？
Which is the real you?
The high schooler or the grown-up?
高校生か 大人か
（夜明）さあ どっちでしょう？
Gee, I wonder.
Which do you think?
“いくつに見える？”って
聞いてくる女並みにうぜえ！
Gross! Like girls who ask
how old you think they are!
I'm a grown-up.
大人ですよ
It's my job to observe and
report about your year here.
僕の仕事は
海崎さんの１年を記録して報告
The rules say the handler
must turn back the clock
サポートするために 担当者は
同じく若返って—
and support the subject as a fellow student.
同行する決まりなんです
ふーん
Why didn't you tell me?
何で それ 黙ってたんだよ？
Well, I just wanted to see that
look of shock on your face!
それはもう 海崎さんの驚く顔が
楽しみで 楽しみで
You sadist!
（海崎）このドＳ！
じゃあ
“去年も３組でした”ってのは？
Then what was that about
being in Class 2-3?
何で 去年もいたんだよ？
Why were you a student last year?
（夜明）研修です
Training.
Training?
研修？
Can't have the supporter struggle to
come to grips with student life.
サポート役が 学生生活に
戸惑ってちゃ 困りますからね
Point.
なるほど
So, how does it feel,
being in high school after so long?
（夜明）で どうですか？
懐かしの高校生活は？
Total train wreck.
（海崎）
どうもこうも さんざんだよ
（夜明）ははっ そのようで
Sure looked like it.
Why make it third year?
何で よりによって３年なんだよ
もう 仲間は出来上がってるし
受験でピリピリし始めるし—
Everyone's got friends,
and they're starting to
freak out about college entrance exams.
It's the toughest year.
一番大変な学年だろう
（夜明）そりゃそうでしょう
（海崎）ん？
Why are you surprised?
I'm pretty sure I told you that ReLIFE is
a program to rehabilitate NEETs.
リライフとは ニートを更生させる
プログラムだと申し上げたはず
Why wouldn't it be tough?
それが ぬるくて
どうするんです？
F...
Fair enough.
それも そっすよね
ご理解 感謝いたします
Thanks for understanding!
今後は なるべく
僕ばかりに頼らずでお願いしますね
Try not to depend on me too much.
No point in being a high schooler
if you just hang out with another adult.
大人が２人でつるんでちゃ
高校生やってる意味ないんで
Got it.
（海崎）分かったよ
I just want to fund this year of my life
and get that job afterward.
俺は ただ １年間の生活保障と
その先の就職口が欲しいだけだ
If I can blend in and stay in the background
all year, that's fine with me.
影薄ーく サラッと
１年過ぎてくれりゃ それでいい
Is that so?
そうですか
Whether you enjoy it or play it safe,
楽しむも 無難に過ごすも
海崎さんの思うがまま—
I think it's best you experience
your ReLIFE however you want.
リライフしてくださるのが
一番だと思います
Oh, right.
あっ そうだ
I won't speak to you formally at school,
so please get used to it.
学校では敬語を使いませんが
ご了承くださいね
Feel free to use casual speech yourself.
海崎さんも
タメ口で構いませんので
おっ おう
O-Okay.
But I guess you always have.
って 最初からタメ口でしたね
You have no manners.
（夜明）なんて 礼儀のない人！
（海崎）むっ…
Well, then.
（夜明）では また明日
See you tomorrow, Arata!
新太！
My first name?!
（海崎）名前呼び!?
（夜明）俺のことも 了でいいよ！
You can call me Ryo, too!
Over my dead body!
呼ばねえよ！
Yeah.
（海崎）うん そう 仕事
A job.
A one-year contract to start.
とりあえず １年契約の
Looks like it could work out, yeah.
まあ 何とかなりそう うん
Say hi to Dad for me.
じゃあ親父にもよろしく
〜♪
ReLIFE Experiment Report
April 8th. First day of school.
（夜明）４月８日 登校初日
Had not checked the schedule,
and was very unprepared.
行事予定の資料に
目を通した様子はなく—
準備不足がうかがえた
While it is impossible to ascertain
how he'll spend the upcoming year...
今後１年間を どう過ごすのか
まだ 未知数ではあるが—
Unlike Subject No. 001,
the failed sample from last year...
昨年の 被験者001の
失敗サンプルとは違い…
Subject No. 002, Kaizaki Arata,
（夜明）被験者002 海崎新太
will surely live a fulfilling ReLIFE.
この先 きっと 充実した
リライフを送ってくれることだろう
NEXT EPISODE
（海崎）夜明さんは
どんな曲 聞くの？
What kind of music
do you listen to, Yoake-san?
（夜明）そうですね
最近の曲は あまり分からないので
Well, I find it hard to
get into modern music.
Same here. All I do is listen to
old tracks on MDs.
（海崎）俺も 昔の曲ばっかりで
今もＭＤで聞いてんだけど
（夜明）“ＭＤ”って何ですか？
What are MDs?
Communication Skills: Zero
（海崎）えっ 知らないの!?
ＭＤ！ ミニディスク！
Wait, you don't know?
MDs! MiniDiscs!